[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：所以这个将是完全微不足道的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So this one's gonna be totally trivial.
所以我会给你解决方案。
So I'm just gonna give you the solution.
我们这么做是因为这会引发下一个问题，好吗？
We're just gonna do this because it's going to set up the next problem, okay?
所以我们将编写一个函数m，它接受一个值并
So we're gonna write a function m that takes a value and
可选的源字符串，并将它们作为对象返回。
an optional source string and returns them as an object.
在这种情况下，不是简单地将内容传递到日志中，
And in this case, instead of simply passing things to the log,
我将使用JSON.stringify来制作对象的字符串
I'm gonna be using JSON.stringify to make strings of the object
因为事实证明object.toString完全没有价值。
because it turns out object.toString is completely worthless.
它不会显示任何有关对象中的内容的信息。
It doesn't show you anything about what's in the object.
只是不值得。
It's just not worth it.
JSON.stringify，另一方面，它在向您展示方面做得相当好
JSON.stringify, on the other hand does a fairly good job of showing you
物体里有什么。
what's in the object.
因此，在这种情况下，m(1)的字符串化是一个值为1且
So, in this case the stringification of m(1) is an object where the value is 1 and
源是字符串1，我们制作字符串的值。
the source is the string 1, we make the string of the value.
如果我们传入第二个参数，
If we pass in a second argument,
那么第二个参数将是source属性。
then that second argument will be the source property.
因此，如果我们传入pi和单词pi，则值将为pi，并且
So if we pass in pi and the word pi, the value will be pi, and
源将是pi。
the source will be pi.
这就是这个函数，这个构造器就是这样做的。
So this is the function, the constructor that does that.
所以继续输入这个，
So go ahead and type this in,
我给你一分钟，然后我们继续，我们将做下一个问题。
I'll give you a minute and then we'll go on and we'll do the next problem.
&gt；&gt；douglas：编写一个函数ADDM，将两个m对象和
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Write a function addm that adds two m objects and
返回m对象。
returns an m object.
所以你可以想象我们可以有一个监管要求，不仅是我们
So you can imagine we could have a regulatory requirement that not only do we
提供结果，我们也提供了关于我们如何获得结果的极端细节。
provide results, we also provide extreme detail on how we obtained the results.
因此，这是一种帮助实现自动化的方法。
So this is a way to help automate that.
因此，如果我将两个m对象相加，我得到一个值为总和的对象
So, if I add two m objects, I get an object where the value is the sum
值，并且源是两个值的级联，
of the values, and the source is the concatenation of the two values,
带着加号的两个来源和他们周围的父母。
of the two sources with a plus sign and parents around them.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：所以，如果我们加上m3和m4，源将是(3+4)。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So, if we add m3 and m4, the source will be (3 + 4).
PI也发生了类似的事情。
And similar thing happening with PI.
好的，这是ADDM。
Okay, so here is addm.
ADDM接受两个m对象，它返回一个新的m
addm takes two m objects, it returns a new m
对象，其中的值将是两个值和字符串的总和，或者
object where the value will be the sum of the two values and the string, or
源将是源的串联。
the source will be the concatenation of the sources.
那么谁有工作呢？
So who got something works?
有没有人用硬的方法做的？
Did anybody do it the hard way?
是的，对象相关编程的第一条规则，让对象完成工作。
Yeah, first rule of object related programming, let the objects do the work.
我们已经有了一个很好的构造函数，我们想要使用它，因为有机会
We already have a nice constructor and we want to use it because there is a chance
我们可能会改变我的所作所为
that we might change what m does and
所以我们希望所有的实例都能利用这一点。
so we want all of the instances to take advantage of that.
所以如果你没收到这个
So if you didn't get this one,
把它写下来，因为我们下一次需要它。
write it down because we're going to need it for the next one.
道格拉斯：好的，我们准备好了吗？
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Okay, are we ready?
因此，编写一个函数liftm，它接受一个二进制函数并
So, write a function liftm that takes a binary function and
一个字符串并返回作用于m个对象的函数。
a string and returns a function that acts on m objects.
所以我们以前做过这个，对吧？
So we've done this before, right?
如果我们将add函数传递给liftm和
If we passed the add function to liftm and
也是加号字符串，它将产生一个与ADDM完全相同的函数。
also the plus string, it will make a function that works exactly like addm.
我们可以做同样的事情，
And we can do the same thing passing,
乘法、星号或任何二进制函数。
multiply, an asterisk or any binary function.
因此，这将帮助我们实现构建过程的自动化
So this will help us to automate the process of building
这个日志算法系统。
this system of journaling arithmetic.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：您需要检查信号源是字符串还是字符串？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Do you need to do the check on the source whether it's string or?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：不，如果我们试着把它和字符串连接起来，它将是强制的
&gt;&gt; Douglas: No, if we try to concatenate it with the strings it will be force to be
一根绳子。
a string.
&gt；&gt；演讲者2：你能再展示一次这个问题吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Can you show the problem again?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：好的，这里是电梯。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Okay, here is liftm.
liftm接受一个二进制函数，并且
liftm takes a binary function and
一个op字符串，它返回一个接受a和b的函数，它返回一个新的m对象
an op string, it returns a function that takes a and b, it returns a new m object
其中该值将是这两个值上的二元函数的结果，以及
where the value will be the result of the binary function on the two values, and
源将是OP字符串的源的串联。
the source will be the concatenation of the sources of the op string.
那么谁得到了升降机，干得好。
So who got liftm, way to go.
那么，如果你们中有人听说过Monads的话？
So, if any of you ever heard of monads?
Monad，Haskell的人一直在谈论他们，你刚刚做了一个Monad，所以
Monads, the Haskell guys talk about them all the time, you just made a monad so
你可以回家告诉你的孩子，今天做了个单曲。
you can go home and tell your kids, made a monad today.
是他干的，好吧。
He did that, all right.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：那么，什么是单子？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So, what is a monad?
&gt；&gt；Douglas：那么，monad是一种可以将函数和
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So, a monad is a thing where you can take functions and
将他们提升到一个更高的水平，在那里他们可以拥有或获得一些新的能力。
lift them up to a higher level where they can have or acquire some new capability.
Haskell社区使用它们是因为Haskell中有一个陷阱。
The Haskell community uses them because there's a trap in Haskell.
Haskell是一种设计出色的语言，
Haskell is a brilliantly designed language and
它的特点之一是它不允许任何形式的突变。
one of the characteristics about it is it does not allow any kind of mutation.
所以所有的函数都是数学意义上的纯函数
So all functions are pure functions in the mathematical sense and
这是一件非常有趣的事情，除了如果你的程序不得不
that's a really interesting thing, except that if your programs have to
与现实世界互动，现实世界是不断变异的，对吧？
interact with the real world, the real world is constantly mutating, right?
像帐户余额这样的东西不可能是一个常数，对吧？
And something like a account balance cannot be a constant, right?
它有一个非常，他们甚至不能在一个可变的系统中做IO，对吗？
It's got a very and they can't even do IO in a mutable system, right?
你不能让任何东西进来，
You can't have anything coming in,
你不能让任何东西出去，因为没有什么可以改变。
you can't have anything going out because nothing can ever change.
所以，这样的事情对他们来说真的很难
So, that kind of made things practically real hard for them and
他们会通过使用高阶函数来解决单子的这个技巧
they'd figure out this trick with monads which by using a higher order functions
以及非常聪明的方式，
and really clever ways,
它们可以有突变的外观，但实际上没有发生任何突变。
they can have the appearance of mutation without actually mutating anything.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：但那是另一次，不管怎么说，你做了一个，所以
&gt;&gt; Douglas: But that's for another time, anyway you made one of those, so
恭喜你。
congratulations.
所以如果你没有写，如果你没有得到这个函数，
So if you didn't write, if you didn't get this function,
你现在应该有它，因为我们马上就会再次使用它。
you should have it now cuz we're gonna use it again in just a second.
大家都准备好继续生活了吗？
So is everybody ready to move on?
好的，这是下一个问题。
Okay, so here's the next problem.
修改函数liftm，使其生成的函数可以接受
Modify function liftm so that the functions it produces can accept
是数字或m对象的参数。
arguments that are either numbers or m objects.
为了让它更容易使用，你可以传入任何数字，
So to make this a little bit easier to use, you can pass in any number,
您不必首先显式地将其包装为m。
you don't have to explicitly wrap it with m first.
所以我们只需要改变电梯就可以了，好吗？
So and we'll just change liftm to do that, okay?
并使其真正灵活，以便您可以传入一个数字或
And make it really flexible so that you can pass in a number or
一个m对象或两个数字，任何组合都可以工作。
an m object or two m objects or two numbers, any combination will work.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：您可以选择三个或
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: You can choose three or
四个参数或&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：不，
four arguments or &gt;&gt; Douglas: No,
这需要两个论点。
it will take two arguments.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：one，liftm或-&gt；&gt；Douglas：或一个数字。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: One, liftm or- &gt;&gt; Douglas: Or a number.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：或者一个数字，好的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Or a number, okay.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：好的，这里是电梯。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Okay, here is liftm.
所以我做的改变就在盒子里。
So the change I made was in the box.
我只是看了一下论点的类型。
I just looked at the type of the argument.
如果它是一个数字，我调用m把它变成一个m对象。
And if it is a number, I call m to turn it into an m object.
那么谁有用的东西呢？
So who got something that works?
非常好。是谁做的艰难的事情？
Very good. Who did it the hard way?
&gt；&gt；[INAUDIBLE]&gt；&gt；Douglas：您没有这样做。
&gt;&gt; [INAUDIBLE] &gt;&gt; Douglas: Where you didn't do that.
[笑]是的，所以物体的第一规则。
[LAUGH] Yeah, so first rule of objects.